LOURDES HURTADO

Miami, Fl 33175 ♦ (786) 266-9517 ♦ lulu_5130@yahoo.com

HUMAN RESOURCES PROFESSIONAL

Extensive background in Human Resources affairs, including experience in employee recruitment and retention, staff development, benefits and compensation, HR records management, HR policies development and legal compliance. I am accustomed to working in fast-paced environment. Strong organizational, analytical, technical and interpersonal skills. Excellent communication skills both written and oral, and comfortable interacting with individuals at executive and non-executive levels. Confident, trustworthy, ethical, detail-oriented and resourceful in task completion. Ability to multitask. Technical skills include: Advanced knowledge of Microsoft Word processing, PowerPoint, Excel (including use of functions and pivot tables. Bilingual with Spanish as a second fluent language.

EDUCATION

Florida International University Degree: Bachelors in Business

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MIAMI LIGHTHOUSE FOR THE BLIND

Human Resources Manager 06/2017 to Present

Responsible for managing the overall human resource functions for the organization. Reporting to the President & CEO and serving on the senior leadership team, the Human Resources Manager assists and advises Miami Lighthouse's managers about Human Resources issues.

- Develops and supports an employee and client-oriented culture that emphasizes quality, continuous improvement, and high performance.
- Manages recruitment efforts to include attracting and retaining qualified candidates, development of job postings, interviewing, administering pre-employment tests, facilitating new-employee orientations and monitoring of introductory periods.
- Maintains records, reporting and personnel files in compliance with federal, state and local laws.
- Develops and updates job descriptions with input from management.
- Thoroughly handling employee grievances, investigations and disciplinary actions.
- Recommends, develops, implements, and updates policies and procedures in the Employee Handbook as needed to ensure compliance with current laws and regulations, and organizational needs and changes.
- Advises members of the management team on employee relations issues and provides guidance for appropriate counseling, coaching or discipline procedures, including terminations.
- Investigates, responds and resolves complaints and concerns from employees in a professional, confidential and timely manner.
- Administers benefits programs and oversees coordination of claims resolution, approval of invoices for payment, and communication of benefits information to employees.
- Develops and implements motivation and recognition programs for staff.
- Collects and provides appropriate employee and volunteer data, or any other HR related information, for grants and contracts.
- Oversees the development and implementation of performance management procedures.
- Coordinates staff trainings to support organizational development.
- Supervises front desk receptionist position.
- Manages the Volunteer Program.
- Coordinate staff trainings to support organizational development.
- Maintains records, reporting and personnel files in compliance with federal, state and local laws.

UNITED STATES MEDICAL SUPPLY

Human Resources Manager 06/2016 to 03/2017

- Develops and administers various human resources plan and procedures for all company personnel.
- Administer and manage company benefits.

LOURDES HURTADO

- Plans, organizes and controls all activities of the department. Participates in developing department goals, objectives and systems.
- Support managers and associates in consistent interpretation and enforcement of policies, procedures, and company practices, including as related to associate coaching/counseling activities.

Phone: (786) 266-9517 • Page 2

- Implements and annually updates the compensation program; rewrites job descriptions as necessary; conducts annual salary surveys and develops merit pool (salary budget); analyzes compensation; monitors the performance evaluation program and revises as necessary.
- Develops, recommends and implements personnel policies and procedures; prepares and maintains
 handbook on policies and procedures; performs benefits administration to include claims resolution, change
 reporting, approving invoices for payment, annual re-evaluation of policies for cost-effectiveness,
 information activities program and cash flow.
- Develops and maintains affirmative action program; files EEO-1 annually; maintains other records, reports and logs to conform to EEO regulations.
- Conducts new-employee orientations; monitors career-path program; new hire benefit orientation and employee relations counseling; conducts exit interviews.
- Establishes and maintains department records and reports. Participates in administrative staff meetings and attends other meetings, such as seminars. Maintains organizational charts and employee directory.
- Evaluates reports, decisions and results of department initiatives in relation to established goals.
 Recommends new approaches, policies and procedures to effect continual improvements in efficiency of department and services performed.
- Ensures compliance with all federal, state and local employment laws.

BULLET LINE, LLC

Sr Human Resources Generalist, 10/2014 to 06/2016

- Employee relations and communication
- Conduct New Hire Orientation
- Maintain and develop employee benefit records, files and logs.
- Support managers and associates in consistent interpretation and enforcement of policies, procedures, and company practices, including as related to associate coaching/counseling activities.
- Provide high level, positive customer support and service.
- Manage Worker's Compensation claims and communication with the legal team and adjusters.
- Administer employee leave of absence programs including tracking of leave and communications to employees; ensure compliance with Department of Labor standards.
- Conduct New Hire Benefit Orientation
- Process group insurance enrollments covering company employees and their dependants.
- Manage vendor invoices and approve for accounting
- Responsible for ensuring maintenance of personnel files and confidentiality of employee's information and records.
- Provide counsel to management team on employee relations matters and Human Resources issues including but not limited to disciplinary actions, terminations.
- Consult with legal counsel on employment issues as appropriate.
- Investigate employee complaints and take timely appropriate action in accordance with company policy.
- Work with the Human Resources team to coordinate employee recognition functions
- Responsible for processing all unemployment compensation claims and inquires

B/E AEROSPACE, CONSUMABLES MANAGEMENT

Human Resources Specialist, 07-2008 to 01-2014

- Over see the US, Canada, and Asia on boarding.
- ◆ Conduct New Hire Benefit Orientation
- Maintain and develop employee benefit records, files and logs.
- Develop and implement processes and procedures.
- Assist employees with any questions or concerns
- Process group insurance enrollments covering company employees and their dependants.
- Provide counseling and support necessary in dealing with employee relations issues and interpretation/application of employment policies and procedures.
- Workers Compensation incidents including temporary employees
 - o Create and maintain OSHA logs
 - o Follow-up with all incidents and trainings
- ◆ Work with management team to develop/coordinate employee development/training program
- Provide support to management level staff in developing personnel procedures.
- Develop companywide procedures and policies and update as needed.
- ◆ Conduct Open Enrollment annually
- Plan, manage, and communicate projects and programs: new computer based programs; employee guide
- Coordinate and implement employee recognition programs and rewards.
- Work with management on employee goals
- Maintain and process all FMLA and Leave of Absence records, payroll and files
- Update HRIS information regarding employees leaves & W/C
- Organize annual eye check-up for Quality insurance employees
- Liaison with corporate benefits regarding, employee questions and concerns
- Conduct training for managers in various areas
- Coordinate and generate all pre-employment and random testing: physical and/or drug test
- ◆ Organize annual 401k seminars
- ◆ BE Well Champion for CM facilities
 - o Coordinate and implement annual health fairs, health initiative
 - o Conduct annual Health Screening